Mohamed Ayoub

2421 E Irwin St, Pierre SD, 57501 | 605-740-5024 | mma.ayoub@outlook.com

Personal Summary

Electrical Engineer graduate of South Dakota State University (SDSU) with 4 years of diversified experience and strong software development skills including in-depth knowledge of Software Development Life Cycle and practical experience with SCRUM and Agile Software Development Model.

Education

AUG. 2015 - MAY 2020 | SOUTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY| BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

Major: Electrical Engineering GPA: 3.2

Minors: Mathematics

Experience

OCT 2020 - SEPT 2023 | IT SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | RAVEN INDUSTRIES INC.

- Product owner and main contributor to our E-Commerce web site for the Agricultural Division. Utilizes Azure Web App, Service Bus Message Queues, Web Job, SQL database, and Visual Studios
- Integrated our E-Commerce web site to Raven's new ERP system. Utilizing C#, Azure Web App, Message Service Bus Queues, Web Job, MSSQL, and Oracle SQL
- Integrated our 3rd party CRM (Salesforce) system with Raven's current ERP system. Utilizes C#, Boomi, and Oracle. Then re-did the integration by building a .NET library (SOAP) for Salesforce and creating .NET console apps to sync data between Raven's current ERP and Salesforce.
- Integrated our IT ticketing system (Ivanti) with Azure DevOps by building a .NET 6 console app
- Developed Salesforce LWC, Aura, and APEX classes to enhance Raven's business processes

JUNE 2020 - AUG. 2020 | BUSINESS ANALYST | FLEXON TECHNOLOGIES

- In-depth knowledge of **Software Development Life Cycle**.
- Extensive experience with **SCRUM** to accommodate requirement changes and **promote flexibility**.
- Ability to **elicit, analyze, gather, document, and prioritize requirements and specifications** for complex and simple projects.
- Extensive experience in **querying SQL databases** for data analysis purposes.

AUG. 2019 - MAY 2020 | SENIOR DESIGN PROJECT | DAKTRONICS

- Designed a device that can gain physical access to the network settings of Daktronics's display controllers (host device) and to reconfigure those network settings as needed.
- Responsible for programming the microprocessor and the C# application that allows the microprocessor to communicate with the host device.
- Created a setup file for the C# application for easy installation of the C# application.
- Designed and built the PCB for the device.

MAY 2018 - AUG. 2019 | APPLICATION ENGINEER INTERN | SENCORE INC.

- Led the software and hardware testing for Sencore and WELLAV products to ensure products met or exceeded specifications.
- Responsible for determining the root cause of customer reported issues and reporting the results to the Application Engineering team for resolution.
- Collaborated with the Engineering department to enhance the stability and performance of development products.

SEPT. 2017 - MAY 2018 | TECHNICIAN | SDSU PERFORMING ARTS CENTER

- Responsible for running wires to the stage speakers and setting up the lighting system.
- Troubleshooting defective equipment during live performances.

Technical Skills

Azure • C# • C • C++ • MATLAB • Python • Verilog • TensorFlow • MPLAB • Batch scripts • Arduino • .NET • MSSQL • Oracle SQL • Azure DevOps • Git • Windows Server • Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu) • JavaScript • HTML • CSS • MS Visio